[
  {
    "id": 2001,
    "question": "crisis",
    "questionDetails": "Todo el mundo a quien preguntas está en crisis.",
    "answer": "crisis, meltdown, seizure",
    "answerDetails": "Everyone you ask says they’re in a crisis."
  },
  {
    "id": 2002,
    "question": "volviendo",
    "questionDetails": "Escuché hoy que estás volviendo con nosotros.",
    "answer": "returning, becoming, getting",
    "answerDetails": "I hear today that you are returning to us."
  },
  {
    "id": 2003,
    "question": "intentado",
    "questionDetails": "Mejores hombres que tú han intentado eso antes.",
    "answer": "tried, attempted, sought",
    "answerDetails": "Better men than you have tried that already."
  },
  {
    "id": 2004,
    "question": "ponerte",
    "questionDetails": "Deberías ponerte mi ropa siempre.",
    "answer": "wear, get",
    "answerDetails": "You should always wear my clothes."
  },
  {
    "id": 2005,
    "question": "sensación",
    "questionDetails": "La sensación del agua contra su piel.",
    "answer": "feeling, sense, sensation",
    "answerDetails": "The feeling of the water against your skin."
  },
  {
    "id": 2006,
    "question": "ambiente",
    "questionDetails": "El líquido se almacena por debajo de la temperatura ambiente.",
    "answer": "ambient, ambience, vibe",
    "answerDetails": "The liquid is stored at below ambient temperature."
  },
  {
    "id": 2007,
    "question": "llamaron",
    "questionDetails": "Lo llamaron, pero él no los oyó.",
    "answer": "they called",
    "answerDetails": "They called him, but he didn’t hear them."
  },
  {
    "id": 2008,
    "question": "súper",
    "questionDetails": "Puedes ser súper sin ellos.",
    "answer": "super",
    "answerDetails": "You can be super without them."
  },
  {
    "id": 2009,
    "question": "confío",
    "questionDetails": "Yo confío de mis ojos.",
    "answer": "trust, entrust",
    "answerDetails": "I trust my own eyes."
  },
  {
    "id": 2010,
    "question": "mandé",
    "questionDetails": "Te mandé un libro, querida.",
    "answer": "sent, mande, mailed",
    "answerDetails": "I sent you a book, hon."
  },
  {
    "id": 2011,
    "question": "misión",
    "questionDetails": "El avión no estaba en la base, sino en una misión, cuando se produjo el ataque.",
    "answer": "assignment",
    "answerDetails": "The aircraft was on assignment away from its base when the attack took place."
  },
  {
    "id": 2012,
    "question": "restaurante",
    "questionDetails": "Tuvimos que cerrar el restaurante.",
    "answer": "restaurant",
    "answerDetails": "We had to close the restaurant."
  },
  {
    "id": 2013,
    "question": "internet",
    "answer": "Internet, online, web"
  },
  {
    "id": 2014,
    "question": "decidió",
    "answer": "Decided"
  },
  {
    "id": 2015,
    "question": "lengua",
    "questionDetails": "Su madre se puso detrás de ella, dando la lengua: “él te tiene en el extremo de una cuerda, ese hombre!.",
    "answer": "tongue",
    "answerDetails": "Her mother stood behind her, giving tongue: ‘He’s got you on the end of a string, that fellow!’."
  },
  {
    "id": 2016,
    "question": "divertido",
    "questionDetails": "Estar en conjunto con el reparto y la tripulación fue muy divertido.",
    "answer": "fun, amusing, entertaining",
    "answerDetails": "Being on set with the cast and crew was really fun."
  },
  {
    "id": 2017,
    "question": "darles",
    "questionDetails": "Cuando me encuentro con méndigos en la calle, nunca sé si darles dinero o comida.",
    "answer": "give them",
    "answerDetails": "When I see beggars on the street, I never know whether to give them money or food."
  },
  {
    "id": 2018,
    "question": "luchar",
    "questionDetails": "Los 2 luchadores de sumo tienen que luchar hasta que uno saque al otro del círculo.",
    "answer": "wrestle",
    "answerDetails": "The sumo wrestlers have to wrestle until one man is pushed out of the circle."
  },
  {
    "id": 2019,
    "question": "defensa",
    "questionDetails": "La defensa está lista para traer su primer testigo.",
    "answer": "defense, defence",
    "answerDetails": "The defense is ready to bring its first witness."
  },
  {
    "id": 2020,
    "question": "espíritu",
    "questionDetails": "Puede ser muy sincero cuando el espíritu lo mueve.",
    "answer": "spirit",
    "answerDetails": "He can be quite candid when the spirit moves him."
  },
  {
    "id": 2021,
    "question": "sales",
    "questionDetails": "Un baño con sales es más relajante.",
    "answer": "salts",
    "answerDetails": "A bath with some salts is more relaxing."
  },
  {
    "id": 2022,
    "question": "pudimos",
    "questionDetails": "Hicimos lo que pudimos.",
    "answer": "could",
    "answerDetails": "We did what we could."
  },
  {
    "id": 2023,
    "question": "desaparecer",
    "questionDetails": "Le di tiempo para desaparecer.",
    "answer": "disappear",
    "answerDetails": "I gave her time to disappear."
  },
  {
    "id": 2024,
    "question": "ayudas",
    "questionDetails": "Ayudas para la contratación de personal especializado.",
    "answer": "aid, help, grants",
    "answerDetails": "Aid for the signing up of specialized personnel."
  },
  {
    "id": 2025,
    "question": "sociales",
    "questionDetails": "Nuestras asignaciones sociales van a quemarse.",
    "answer": "social",
    "answerDetails": "Our social expenditure is set to spiral."
  },
  {
    "id": 2026,
    "question": "versión",
    "questionDetails": "La versión de los acontecimientos de Marco no coincide con la de Gloria.",
    "answer": "version, rendering",
    "answerDetails": "Marco’s version of events does not match Gloria’s."
  },
  {
    "id": 2027,
    "question": "mismas",
    "questionDetails": "El peso y estatura son las mismas.",
    "answer": "same, themselves, thereof",
    "answerDetails": "Height and weight are about the same."
  },
  {
    "id": 2028,
    "question": "descubrir",
    "questionDetails": "Me levanto y me voy a la oficina, para descubrir que es domingo.",
    "answer": "discover",
    "answerDetails": "I get up and go to my office, only to discover that it is Sunday."
  },
  {
    "id": 2029,
    "question": "continuar",
    "questionDetails": "El ensayo clínico no continuará después de estos problemas.",
    "answer": "continue, proceed",
    "answerDetails": "The clinical trial will not continue after these problems."
  },
  {
    "id": 2030,
    "question": "cerebro",
    "questionDetails": "El cerebro es el órgano más importante del cuerpo.",
    "answer": "brain",
    "answerDetails": "The brain is the most important organ in the body."
  },
  {
    "id": 2031,
    "question": "plaza",
    "questionDetails": "Fueron a la plaza para comprar frutas frescas.",
    "answer": "market",
    "answerDetails": "They went to the market to buy fresh fruit."
  },
  {
    "id": 2032,
    "question": "pedazo",
    "questionDetails": "No pude acabarme la comida y dejé un pedazo de carne en el plato.",
    "answer": "piece, chunk",
    "answerDetails": "I couldn’t finish my meal and I left a piece of meat on the plate."
  },
  {
    "id": 2033,
    "question": "sacando",
    "questionDetails": "Están sacando la alfombra según hablamos.",
    "answer": "pulling, taking, scooping",
    "answerDetails": "They are pulling the rug as we speak."
  },
  {
    "id": 2034,
    "question": "regaló",
    "questionDetails": "Me lo regaló él.",
    "answer": "gave, gifted",
    "answerDetails": "He gave it to me."
  },
  {
    "id": 2035,
    "question": "mataron",
    "questionDetails": "Los rebeldes asaltaron los pueblos y mataron a mujeres y niños de manera indiscriminada.",
    "answer": "they killed, they were killed",
    "answerDetails": "The rebels stormed villages and they killed women and children indiscriminately."
  },
  {
    "id": 2036,
    "question": "club",
    "questionDetails": "Vamos a ir a un nuevo club del centro.",
    "answer": "club",
    "answerDetails": "Some of us are going downtown to a new club."
  },
  {
    "id": 2037,
    "question": "modelo",
    "questionDetails": "Modelos de cera fueron utilizados por los escultores en el método de cera perdida de fundición de bronce.",
    "answer": "model, design, pattern",
    "answerDetails": "Wax models were used by sculptors in the lost wax method of bronze casting."
  },
  {
    "id": 2038,
    "question": "pienses",
    "questionDetails": "No pienses en nada más.",
    "answer": "think",
    "answerDetails": "Think of nothing else."
  },
  {
    "id": 2039,
    "question": "cobarde",
    "questionDetails": "Un farsante, mentiroso y cobarde.",
    "answer": "coward",
    "answerDetails": "A fake, he’s a liar and a coward."
  },
  {
    "id": 2040,
    "question": "campeón",
    "questionDetails": "Su campeón es franco en su propósito.",
    "answer": "champion",
    "answerDetails": "Your champion is bold to his purpose."
  },
  {
    "id": 2041,
    "question": "jesús",
    "answer": "Jesus"
  },
  {
    "id": 2042,
    "question": "secretos",
    "questionDetails": "Mis secretos están seguros con ella.",
    "answer": "secrets",
    "answerDetails": "My secrets are safe with her."
  },
  {
    "id": 2043,
    "question": "seamos",
    "questionDetails": "Quiero que seamos amigos de nuevo.",
    "answer": "be",
    "answerDetails": "I want to be friends again."
  },
  {
    "id": 2044,
    "question": "conseguí",
    "answer": "Got"
  },
  {
    "id": 2045,
    "question": "mías",
    "questionDetails": "Las trampas de abajo son mías.",
    "answer": "mine",
    "answerDetails": "Traps down there are mine."
  },
  {
    "id": 2046,
    "question": "carácter",
    "questionDetails": "Su arrebato estaba enteramente en el carácter.",
    "answer": "character",
    "answerDetails": "His outburst was entirely in character."
  },
  {
    "id": 2047,
    "question": "iguales",
    "questionDetails": "No todos los hombres son creados iguales.",
    "answer": "equal, alike, same",
    "answerDetails": "All men are not created equal."
  },
  {
    "id": 2048,
    "question": "fiestas",
    "questionDetails": "¿Se van a algún lado para las fiestas?",
    "answer": "holidays, holiday season",
    "answerDetails": "Are you going anywhere for the holidays?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2049,
    "question": "tontería",
    "questionDetails": "Valerie alegró nuestro ánimo sombrío con su tontería.",
    "answer": "silliness",
    "answerDetails": "Valerie brightened up our somber mood with her silliness."
  },
  {
    "id": 2050,
    "question": "respirar",
    "questionDetails": "Deje que su césped respirar por poner aire en el suelo.",
    "answer": "breathe",
    "answerDetails": "Let your lawn breathe by putting air into the soil."
  },
  {
    "id": 2051,
    "question": "cumple",
    "questionDetails": "Cumple una condena de 6 años en una cárcel estatal.",
    "answer": "he serves",
    "answerDetails": "He serves a 6-year sentence in a state prison."
  },
  {
    "id": 2052,
    "question": "pagado",
    "questionDetails": "Había pagado un precio muy alto.",
    "answer": "paid",
    "answerDetails": "I paid too high a price."
  },
  {
    "id": 2053,
    "question": "fumar",
    "questionDetails": "Fumar está prohibido en lugares públicos cerrados.",
    "answer": "smoking, smoke",
    "answerDetails": "Smoking is prohibited in closed public spaces."
  },
  {
    "id": 2054,
    "question": "pedro",
    "questionDetails": "Pedro se fue a la playa para pescar.",
    "answer": "peter",
    "answerDetails": "Peter went to the beach to go fishing."
  },
  {
    "id": 2055,
    "question": "gloria",
    "questionDetails": "El barco fue soplado a la gloria.",
    "answer": "glory",
    "answerDetails": "The boat was blown to glory."
  },
  {
    "id": 2056,
    "question": "primo",
    "questionDetails": "Primo (a) Hermano (a).",
    "answer": "cousin",
    "answerDetails": "First cousin."
  },
  {
    "id": 2057,
    "question": "entrevista",
    "questionDetails": "Creo que la entrevista ha terminado.",
    "answer": "interview",
    "answerDetails": "I guess the interview’s over."
  },
  {
    "id": 2058,
    "question": "entere",
    "questionDetails": "Ya verás cuando se entere de mi regalo de bodas.",
    "answer": "hears, learns, know",
    "answerDetails": "Wait till he hears about my wedding present."
  },
  {
    "id": 2059,
    "question": "sufrir",
    "questionDetails": "y otras palabras y definiciones pueden sufrir cambios",
    "answer": "undergo",
    "answerDetails": "and other words and definitions may undergo changes"
  },
  {
    "id": 2060,
    "question": "hablaste",
    "questionDetails": "Hablaste con tu tía sobre lo del carro, ¿no?",
    "answer": "you talked",
    "answerDetails": "You talked to your aunt about the car, right?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2061,
    "question": "andaba",
    "questionDetails": "Papá nunca andaba cerca.",
    "answer": "was",
    "answerDetails": "Dad was never around."
  },
  {
    "id": 2062,
    "question": "baile",
    "questionDetails": "El príncipe la invitó al baile.",
    "answer": "ball",
    "answerDetails": "The prince invited her to the ball."
  },
  {
    "id": 2063,
    "question": "explicación",
    "questionDetails": "Se marchó sin ninguna explicación.",
    "answer": "explanation",
    "answerDetails": "She left without an explanation."
  },
  {
    "id": 2064,
    "question": "agarra",
    "questionDetails": "Agarra el otro extremo de esto.",
    "answer": "grab",
    "answerDetails": "Grab the other end of this."
  },
  {
    "id": 2065,
    "question": "buscarlo",
    "questionDetails": "No tengo el número de teléfono del Mecánico. ¿Puedes buscarlo?",
    "answer": "look it up",
    "answerDetails": "I don’t know the mechanic’s phone number. Can you look it up?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2066,
    "question": "ponerse",
    "questionDetails": "Sólo hay que ponerse en esa postura.",
    "answer": "get",
    "answerDetails": "You only have to get in that position."
  },
  {
    "id": 2067,
    "question": "punta",
    "questionDetails": "Él me enseñó la punta de su lengua.",
    "answer": "tip, rush, peak",
    "answerDetails": "He showed me the tip of his tongue."
  },
  {
    "id": 2068,
    "question": "internacional",
    "questionDetails": "Derecho internacional.",
    "answer": "international",
    "answerDetails": "International law."
  },
  {
    "id": 2069,
    "question": "libros",
    "questionDetails": "Disfruten juntos de los libros con rimas.",
    "answer": "books, textbooks, workbooks",
    "answerDetails": "Enjoy rhyming books together."
  },
  {
    "id": 2070,
    "question": "existen",
    "questionDetails": "Pero existen hipótesis que compiten también.",
    "answer": "exist",
    "answerDetails": "But competing hypotheses exist as well."
  },
  {
    "id": 2071,
    "question": "corriente",
    "questionDetails": "Será más difícil ir en canoa al norte porque estaremos remando contra la corriente.",
    "answer": "stream, running, flow",
    "answerDetails": "It will be more difficult to canoe north because we’ll be rowing against the stream."
  },
  {
    "id": 2072,
    "question": "uso",
    "questionDetails": "El pintor siguió el uso religioso y costumbre de su tiempo.",
    "answer": "use, usage, application",
    "answerDetails": "The painter followed the religious use and wont of his time."
  },
  {
    "id": 2073,
    "question": "serás",
    "questionDetails": "Natalia, ¿serás mi esposa?",
    "answer": "will you be",
    "answerDetails": "Natalia, will you be my wife?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2074,
    "question": "pegado",
    "questionDetails": "Todos los imanes estaban pegados al lado de la nevera.",
    "answer": "stuck",
    "answerDetails": "All of the magnets were stuck to the side of the fridge."
  },
  {
    "id": 2075,
    "question": "figura",
    "questionDetails": "Tener buena figura.",
    "answer": "figure",
    "answerDetails": "To have a good figure."
  },
  {
    "id": 2076,
    "question": "naturaleza",
    "questionDetails": "Es en la naturaleza de las cosas que la mayoría de los premios de música se establecen para los artistas intérpretes en lugar de compositores.",
    "answer": "nature, wild",
    "answerDetails": "It is in the nature of things that the majority of music prizes get set up for performers rather than composers."
  },
  {
    "id": 2077,
    "question": "sentado",
    "questionDetails": "Estabas sentado en la silla cuando te dormiste.",
    "answer": "seated",
    "answerDetails": "You were seated in the chair when you fell asleep."
  },
  {
    "id": 2078,
    "question": "blanca",
    "questionDetails": "Trajimos algo de arena blanca.",
    "answer": "white",
    "answerDetails": "We got us some white sand."
  },
  {
    "id": 2079,
    "question": "chiquita",
    "answer": "Chiquita, little girl"
  },
  {
    "id": 2080,
    "question": "operación",
    "questionDetails": "Es una operación legítima.",
    "answer": "operation",
    "answerDetails": "This is a legitimate operation, okay?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2081,
    "question": "informe",
    "questionDetails": "La tesorera le dio su informe de presupuesto al comité.",
    "answer": "report",
    "answerDetails": "The treasurer gave her budget report to the committee."
  },
  {
    "id": 2082,
    "question": "pista",
    "questionDetails": "Los perros solo pudieron seguir su pista hasta la frontera con México.",
    "answer": "track, court, runway",
    "answerDetails": "Their dogs could follow the track only as far as the Mexican border."
  },
  {
    "id": 2083,
    "question": "ando",
    "answer": "Ando"
  },
  {
    "id": 2084,
    "question": "pistola",
    "questionDetails": "El hombre guardó la pistola en un cajón con llave.",
    "answer": "gun, pistol",
    "answerDetails": "The man put his gun away in a locked drawer."
  },
  {
    "id": 2085,
    "question": "mercado",
    "questionDetails": "El mercado del Reino Unido permaneció en recesión.",
    "answer": "market",
    "answerDetails": "The UK market remained in recession."
  },
  {
    "id": 2086,
    "question": "imaginas",
    "questionDetails": "Puedo saber que imaginas.",
    "answer": "imagine",
    "answerDetails": "I can hardly see what you imagine."
  },
  {
    "id": 2087,
    "question": "condición",
    "questionDetails": "Sorprendentemente, estar casado era una condición obligatoria para solicitar el puesto.",
    "answer": "condition",
    "answerDetails": "Surprisingly, being married was a mandatory condition to apply for the job."
  },
  {
    "id": 2088,
    "question": "cine",
    "questionDetails": "Escribe artículos sobre cine y literatura para el periódico local.",
    "answer": "film, cinema, movies",
    "answerDetails": "He writes articles on film and literature for the local Paper."
  },
  {
    "id": 2089,
    "question": "humor",
    "questionDetails": "El profesor estaba de buen humor y no tenemos deberes para hoy.",
    "answer": "mood, humour",
    "answerDetails": "The teacher was in a good mood, and we have no homework for today."
  },
  {
    "id": 2090,
    "question": "denuncia",
    "questionDetails": "Rafael llamó a la policía para registrar una denuncia contra sus vecinos escandalosos.",
    "answer": "complaint",
    "answerDetails": "Rafael called the police to make a complaint against his noisy neighbors."
  },
  {
    "id": 2091,
    "question": "veremos",
    "questionDetails": "Veremos un cortometraje sobre la vida en Perú y después comentaremos su contenido.",
    "answer": "we will watch",
    "answerDetails": "We will watch a short movie about life in Peru and then we will comment on its content."
  },
  {
    "id": 2092,
    "question": "calidad",
    "questionDetails": "Calidad de vida.",
    "answer": "quality",
    "answerDetails": "Quality of life."
  },
  {
    "id": 2093,
    "question": "supiera",
    "questionDetails": "Ojalá yo lo supiera.",
    "answer": "knew",
    "answerDetails": "I wish i knew."
  },
  {
    "id": 2094,
    "question": "temas",
    "questionDetails": "Si supiera qué temas van a salir.",
    "answer": "topics, themes, issues",
    "answerDetails": "I wonder what topics will come up."
  },
  {
    "id": 2095,
    "question": "gratis",
    "questionDetails": "La mantuve fuera del viento y navegando gratis hasta que tenía todo cuadrado hacia adelante.",
    "answer": "free",
    "answerDetails": "I kept her off the wind and sailing free until I had all square forward."
  },
  {
    "id": 2096,
    "question": "quedaste",
    "questionDetails": "Pero tú te quedaste y no pasó nada.",
    "answer": "stayed",
    "answerDetails": "But you stayed on and nothing happened."
  },
  {
    "id": 2097,
    "question": "pobres",
    "questionDetails": "La brecha entre los ricos y los pobres se ha ampliado.",
    "answer": "poor",
    "answerDetails": "The gap between the rich and the poor has widened."
  },
  {
    "id": 2098,
    "question": "pasos",
    "questionDetails": "El padre de Vicente fue barbero antes que él, y ahora le sigue los pasos.",
    "answer": "footsteps",
    "answerDetails": "Vicente’s father was a barber before him, and now he’s following in his footsteps."
  },
  {
    "id": 2099,
    "question": "serie",
    "questionDetails": "¿Cuál es tu serie preferida en este momento?",
    "answer": "series, serial",
    "answerDetails": "What’s your favorite series right now?"
  },
  {
    "id": 2100,
    "question": "excusa",
    "questionDetails": "Pero sigue sin ser una excusa.",
    "answer": "excuse",
    "answerDetails": "But that’s still no excuse."
  }
]